cogconnected.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy - COGconnected

**Privacy Policy**

  1. **Introduction**

1.1    We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors; in this policy we explain how we will handle your personal data.

1.2    We will ask you to consent to our use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy when you first visit our website.

  2. **Credit**

2.1    This document was created using a template from Docular (https://docular.net).

  3. **How we use your personal data**

3.1    In this Section 3 we have set out:

(a)    the general categories of personal data that we may process;

(b)    in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and specific categories of that data;

(c)    the purposes for which we may process personal data; and

(d)    the legal bases of the processing.

3.2    We may process data about your use of our website and services (“ **usage data** “). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

3.3    We may process your account data (“ **account data** “). The account data may include your name and email address. The source of the account data is either directly from you or via your Steam Account, but only with your explicit permission. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

3.4    We may process your information included in your personal profile on our website (“ **profile data** “). The profile data may include your name, email address, profile pictures, gender, date of birth, relationship status, interests and hobbies, educational details and employment details. The profile data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

3.5    We may process your personal data that is provided in the course of the use of our services (“ **service data** “). The service data may include the timing, frequency and pattern of service use. The source of the service data is you. The service data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

3.6    We may process information that you post for publication on our website or through our services (“ **publication data** “). The publication data may be processed for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

3.7    We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (“ **notification data** “). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.

3.8    We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“ **correspondence data** “). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users.

3.9    In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 3, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

3.10  Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.

  4. **Providing your personal data to others**

4.1    We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group of companies (this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this policy.

4.2    We may disclose your personal data to our insurers and/or professional advisers insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining and maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice and managing legal disputes.

4.3    We may disclose email addresses to our suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for sending you our email newsletter, if you have requested it (you can inform us at any time if you no longer require the newsletter).

4.4    We may disclose your enquiry data to one or more of those selected third party suppliers of goods and services identified on our website for the purpose of enabling them to contact you so that they can offer, market and sell to you relevant goods and/or services. Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to the enquiry data that we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party’s use of your personal data.

4.5    In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 4, we may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

  5. **International transfers of your personal data**

5.1    In this Section 5, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

5.2    The hosting facilities for our website are situated in US, Europe and UK. The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

5.3    Mailing databases are situated in US and Australia. The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely  EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield.

5.4    You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.

  6. **Retaining and deleting personal data**

6.1    This Section 6 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

6.2    Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

6.3    We will retain and delete your personal data as follows:

(a)    Profile data containing personal data will be retained for two years following your last login, if you have not logged in for over two years, you will be notified of this. If we have not received notification within 30 days of your intent to use your account we will delete your profile data and notify you of this deletion.

(b)    Cookie data will be retained for no longer than 30 days.

6.4    Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

  7. **Amendments**

7.1    We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.

7.2    You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

7.3    We may notify you of changes to this policy by email or through the private messaging system on our website.

  8. **Your rights**

8.1    You may instruct us to provide you with any personal information we hold about you; provision of such information will be subject to:

(a)    the first request for information being free of charge. Any subsequent requests are subjected to a CAD 20 administration fee; and

(b)    the supply of appropriate evidence of your identity (for this purpose, we will usually accept a photocopy of your passport certified by a solicitor or bank plus an original copy of a utility bill showing your current address).

8.2    We may withhold personal information that you request to the extent permitted by law.

8.3    You may instruct us at any time not to process your personal information for marketing purposes.

8.4    In practice, you will usually either expressly agree in advance to our use of your personal information for marketing purposes, or we will provide you with an opportunity to opt out of the use of your personal information for marketing purposes.

  9. **About cookies**

9.1    A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

9.2    Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

9.3    Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

  10. **Cookies that we use**

10.1  We use cookies for the following purposes:

(a)    authentication – we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website;

(b)    status – we use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website;

(d)    security – we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally;

(e)    advertising – we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you (cookies used for this purpose are: Quantcast, Amazon Associates, Google Adsense, DoubleClick, ShareThis, DoubleClick Spotlight, Index Exchange, AppNexus, eXelate, ScoreCard Research Beacon, DoubleVerify, Aggregate Knowledge, Media Innovation Group, Taboola, Tapad, Semasio, Drawbridge, Moat, Teads, Google Publisher Tags, Google Safeframe, Google Pingback, Google Adsense Asytnchronous, Facebook impressions, Sortable, Google Ads Measurements.);

(f)    analysis – we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services (cookies used for this purpose are: Google Analytics, ComScore, Google Tag Manager, Crazy Egg, Facebook Audience, Google Analytics Audience);

(g)    cookie consent – we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally.

  11. **Cookies used by our service providers**

11.1  Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.

11.2  We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.

11.3  We publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website. These are tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: https://adssettings.google.com. You can also opt out of the AdSense partner network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: http://optout.networkadvertising.org. However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you may wish to consider using the Google browser plug-ins available at: https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996.

11.4  We use Avocet, Sortable and Google Audiences to carry out retargeting and Header Bidding. These service uses cookies for retargeting ads and targeting ads based on your interests. You can view the privacy policy of these service providers at <http://avocet.io/privacy-policy>, <https://sortable.com/privacy-legal/> and <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

  12. **Managing cookies**

12.1  Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a)    https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);

(b)    https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);

(c)    http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);

(d)    https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);

(e)    https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and

(f)    https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).

12.2  Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

12.3  If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

  13. **Our details**

13.1  This website is owned and operated by COGconnected.

13.2  We are registered in Canada and our registered office is located in Abbotsford, BC.

13.3  Our principal place of business is located Abbotsford, BC

13.4  You can contact us:

(a)    by post, simply contact us for the postal address;

(b)    by email, using this email address [gamecanadian@gmail.com](mailto:gamecanadian@gmail.com)
